

# **Hector Castillo**

hectorcast25@gmail.com +34 677839341 Barcelona,Spain

A Front-end developer and designer with 2+ years experience. I have a clear understanding of web design with skills in creating web pages with HTML5, CSS3, Responsive web design and bootstrap 4. I also enjoy working with JavaScript and JS frameworks, such as Scriptaculous, Dojo and jQuery with some experience with version control system APIs (Github). I have worked as a Junior Quality Assurance Engineer for mobile and desktop applications. I am now looking for a position that fosters my interest in collaborating in the development department.

# **Experience**

# BeMobile Quality Assurance Engineer - Internship

Nov 2021 - Dec 2022

Barcelona, Spain-Hybrid

- Testing software to check its function and manually document errors found
- Developing testing procedures to track product issues more effectively and efficiently
- Creating a test plan in Software TestRail and BrowserStack
- Testing in BrowserStack, mobile testing platform and websites of the developed applications
- Experience with JIRATesting software to check its function and manually document errors found

**Skills:** Analytical Skills · TestTrail · Software Development · Android Development

# Greens Beans School Frontend Developer, Self-employed

Oct 2021 - May 2022

Barcelona, Spain · On-site

- Developing the website in Webflow
- Reviewing and correcting responsive code errors
- Adapting website to responsive design criteria delivered in Figma format

Skills: Content Management Systems (CMS) WebFlow

#### D'ventos de bodas

#### Taste and Celebration · InternshipTaste and Celebration

Jan 2021- Jan 2022

Madrid, Spain · Remote

- Responsible for the front end development for the website in Wordpress
- Creating a fully functional WordPress website depending on business needs and design specifications
- Building compelling and accessible UI experiences with CSS3, JavaScript, and JQuery support and accessibility based on Photoshop designs from the team's designers

**Skills:** CSS 3 · widgets · WordPress · Elementor

## **Education**

#### Intalentia Innovation

### Basic web design and advance web design

Feb 2022- July 2022

Barcelona, Spain · On-site

- Introduction to web design and web design with JavScript language
- HTML and CSS3, style to text, forms, table, structure of anchors, format image and how to upload a web page
- Basic procedure of XML language
- Complement the knowledge of html language to make the web page dynamic and interactive

#### Cepi-Base

#### Front- End Web Development

Feb 2022- Abril 2023

Barcelona, Spain · On-site

- HTML5, CSS3, BOOTSTRAP4, JavaScript
- JavaScript frameworks: jQuery, JQuery Effects, Widgets, Dojo, Scriptaculous, Prototype
- Functional Testing
- SQL and Python

#### **Tokio School Madrid**

### Post graduate program: Front- End Web Development

sept 2020 - Sep 2022

Madrid, Spain · Remote

- B2 level (Common European Framework of Reference for Language) in English
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Responsive design, Version control/Git

### **Tech Skills**

#### HTML5, CSS3, BOOTSTRAP FRAMEWORK

2 + years experience working with HTML5, CSS3 and Bootstrap 4. I like to work in my own code to create static web pages with HTML5 and CSS3 and give them a little bit of interactivity with advanced CSS3 like canvas and RWD (Responsive web design). I also like to work with Bootstrap 4 because of the creative opportunity you can find through HTML and CSS templates as well as JavaScript Plugins.

#### **JAVASCRIPT**

1.5 years experience working with Javascript. I like to work in my own code using Javascript and complement it with HTML and CSS3.

#### Interests and pursuits

**SQL**-I have recently started learning SQL (Structured Query Language) working with a *RDBMS* MySQL because I would like to deepen my knowledge about managing and organising data in databases.

**Python**-I am currently learning how to use Python in both Frontend and Backend programming projects. I find it particularly interesting as it is an incredibly versatile programming language.

**React JS**-I have a keen interest in studying ReactJS because I can make better web interfaces and it is a useful tool for building Single Page Applications (SPA).

**Sass/css** - I am completing a project using SASS and I am curious as to how variables, nested rules, mixins, imports can be used as features along with CSS.